
var quiz = {
    "JS": [

   {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "Friday is the 4th day of the month, then what will be 19th?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Saturday",
    "b": "Sunday",
    "c": "Friday",
    "d": "Monday"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Saturday",
    "score": 0,
    "status": "a"
    },
    // -----------------------------end-----------
        // ---------------------------start--------
    {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "A man walks north, then turn left after some distance he turns right, what is his position?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "East",
    "b": "West",
    "c": "South",
    "d": "North"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "East",
    "score": 0,
    "status": "a"
    },
    // -----------------------------end-----------
        // ---------------------------start--------
    {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "Why we boil milk?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "To kill germs",
    "b": "To purify it",
    "c": "To make it tasty",
    "d": "None of these"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "To kill germs",
    "score": 0,
    "status": "a"
    },
    // -----------------------------end-----------
        // ---------------------------start--------
    {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "If a car moves 60 km per hour and train is twice the speed of car. Then how much distance train will cover in 30 minutes in km?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "30",
    "b": "60",
    "c": "40",
    "d": "120"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "60",
    "score": 0,
    "status": "a"
    },
    // -----------------------------end-----------

        // ---------------------------start--------
    {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "How many months have 31 days?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "6",
    "b": "11",
    "c": "8",
    "d": "7"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "7",
    "score": 0,
    "status": "a"
    },
    // -----------------------------end-----------
        // ---------------------------start--------
    {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "Out of 500, 360 are boys, find the percentage of girls?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "30%",
    "b": "36%",
    "c": "28%",
    "d": "40%"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "28%",
    "score": 0,
    "status": "a"
    },
    // -----------------------------end-----------
        // ---------------------------start--------
    {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "If 4th day of the month is tuesday, then what will be 26th?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Monday",
    "b": "Tuesday",
    "c": "Wednesday",
    "d": "Sunday"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Wednesday",
    "score": 0,
    "status": "a"
    },
    // -----------------------------end-----------
        // ---------------------------start--------
    {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "Which one is out of list?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Horse",
    "b": "Cow",
    "c": "Sheep",
    "d": "Buffalo"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Horse",
    "score": 0,
    "status": "a"
    },
    // -----------------------------end-----------
        // ---------------------------start--------
    {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "A man purchased book in 30 and sell in 40, what is the percentage of profit?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "10%",
    "b": "33.33%",
    "c": "50%",
    "d": "44%"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "33.33%",
    "score": 0,
    "status": "a"
    },
    // -----------------------------end-----------
        // ---------------------------start--------
    {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "What will come next in the following series 2 4 6 10 14 18 24 26...?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "28",
    "b": "30",
    "c": "32",
    "d": "26"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "28",
    "score": 0,
    "status": "a"
    },
    // -----------------------------end-----------
        // ---------------------------start--------
    {
    "id": 11,
    "question": "What is the percentage of 90% of 90?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "89",
    "b": "72",
    "c": "18",
    "d": "81"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "81",
    "score": 0,
    "status": "a"
    },
    // -----------------------------end-----------
        // ---------------------------start--------
    {
    "id": 12,
    "question": "Sister of my brother'e son is my.......?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Niece",
    "b": "Cousin",
    "c": "Cousin-sister",
    "d": "All of these"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Niece",
    "score": 0,
    "status": "a"
    },
    // -----------------------------end-----------


    
   
   
   
        // ---------------------------start--------
    {
    "id": 13,
    "question": "What will come next in the following series A C F J...?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "L",
    "b": "M",
    "c": "N",
    "d": "O"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "O",
    "score": 0,
    "status": "a"
    },
    // -----------------------------end-----------
        // ---------------------------start--------
    {
    "id": 14,
    "question": "Find the vowel in the following series?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "B",
    "b": "C",
    "c": "U",
    "d": "F"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "U",
    "score": 0,
    "status": "a"
    },
    // -----------------------------end-----------
        // ---------------------------start--------
    {
    "id": 15,
    "question": "What will come next in the following series A C F.....?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "G",
    "b": "J",
    "c": "H",
    "d": "I"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "J",
    "score": 0,
    "status": "a"
    },
    // -----------------------------end-----------
        // ---------------------------start--------
    {
    "id": 16,
    "question": "Which one is different from the rest?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Carrot",
    "b": "Onion",
    "c": "Fish",
    "d": "Potato"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Fish",
    "score": 0,
    "status": "a"
    },
    // -----------------------------end---------
        // ---------------------------start--------
    {
    "id": 17,
    "question": "What will come next in the following series 80 2 40 4 20 6....?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "5",
    "b": "10",
    "c": "8",
    "d": "12"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "10",
    "score": 0,
    "status": "a"
    },
    // -----------------------------end---------
        // ---------------------------start--------
    {
    "id": 18,
    "question": "Out of 500 students, 340 are present, find the percentage of absent?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "32",
    "b": "40",
    "c": "44",
    "d": "34"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "32",
    "score": 0,
    "status": "a"
    },
    // -----------------------------end---------
        // ---------------------------start--------
    {
    "id": 19,
    "question": "If 15th day of the month is Monday then what will be 4th?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Tuesday",
    "b": "Wednesday",
    "c": "Thursday",
    "d": "Sunday"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Thursday",
    "score": 0,
    "status": "a"
    },
    // -----------------------------end---------
        // ---------------------------start--------
    {
    "id": 20,
    "question": "Which one is different from the rest?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Hockey",
    "b": "Football",
    "c": "Cricket",
    "d": "Tennis"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Football",
    "score": 0,
    "status": "a"
    },
    // -----------------------------end---------
        // ---------------------------start--------
    {
    "id": 21,
    "question": "5 men write 5 pages in 5 minutes, then how much pages will 1 mn write in 5 minutes?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "5",
    "b": "1",
    "c": "3",
    "d": "2"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "1",
    "score": 0,
    "status": "a"
    },
    // -----------------------------end---------
        // ---------------------------start--------
    {
    "id": 22,
    "question": "Motorcycle is to petrol as trunk is to......?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Diesel",
    "b": "Greece",
    "c": "Tyre",
    "d": "Steering"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Diesel",
    "score": 0,
    "status": "a"
    },
    // -----------------------------end---------
        // ---------------------------start--------
    {
    "id": 23,
    "question": "A man purchased book in 100 and sold in 150, find the percentage of profit?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "100",
    "b": "50",
    "c": "150",
    "d": "25"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "50",
    "score": 0,
    "status": "a"
    },
    // -----------------------------end---------
        // ---------------------------start--------
    {
    "id": 24,
    "question": "What will come next in the following series 66 63 57 45....?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "32",
    "b": "31",
    "c": "21",
    "d": "22"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "21",
    "score": 0,
    "status": "a"
    },
    // -----------------------------end---------
        // ---------------------------start--------
    {
    "id": 25,
    "question": "If Saturday is the 14th day of the month, then what will be 4th?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Wednesday",
    "b": "Friday",
    "c": "Saturday",
    "d": "Monday"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Wednesday",
    "score": 0,
    "status": "a"
    },
    // -----------------------------end---------
        // ---------------------------start--------
    {
    "id": 26,
    "question": "What will come next in the following series 4 16 64  ....  1024",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "252",
    "b": "156",
    "c": "256",
    "d": "556"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "256",
    "score": 0,
    "status": "a"
    },
    // -----------------------------end---------
        // ---------------------------start--------
    {
    "id": 27,
    "question": "2+2/2....?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "9",
    "b": "3",
    "c": "4",
    "d": "6"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "3",
    "score": 0,
    "status": "a"
    },
    // -----------------------------end---------
        // ---------------------------start--------
    {
    "id": 28,
    "question": "Which vitamin do we get from Sunlight?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "A",
    "b": "B",
    "c": "C",
    "d": "D"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "D",
    "score": 0,
    "status": "a"
    },
    // -----------------------------end---------
        // ---------------------------start--------
    {
    "id": 29,
    "question": "20% of one tenth of 90 is?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "9",
    "b": "18",
    "c": "27",
    "d": "36"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "18",
    "score": 0,
    "status": "a"
    },
    // -----------------------------end---------
        // ---------------------------start--------
    {
    "id": 30,
    "question": "One third of 90 is?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "18",
    "b": "30",
    "c": "37",
    "d": "45"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "30",
    "score": 0,
    "status": "a"
    },
    // -----------------------------end---------
        // ---------------------------start--------
    {
    "id": 31,
    "question": "In English alphabet which letter is at 10th place from right?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "P",
    "b": "Q",
    "c": "R",
    "d": "S"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Q",
    "score": 0,
    "status": "a"
    },
    // -----------------------------end---------
        // ---------------------------start--------
    {
    "id": 32,
    "question": "What will come next in the following series 100 4 50 8 25 16....?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "32",
    "b": "12.5",
    "c": "6.25",
    "d": "24"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "12.5",
    "score": 0,
    "status": "a"
    },
    // -----------------------------end---------
        // ---------------------------start--------
    {
    "id": 33,
    "question": "What will come next A E K.....?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "J",
    "b": "R",
    "c": "M",
    "d": "S"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "S",
    "score": 0,
    "status": "a"
    },
    // -----------------------------end---------
        // ---------------------------start--------
    {
    "id": 34,
    "question": "In a class of 150 students 100 are girls, find the percentage of boys?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "33.33",
    "b": "50",
    "c": "42",
    "d": "25.55"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "33.33",
    "score": 0,
    "status": "a"
    },
    // -----------------------------end---------
        // ---------------------------start--------
    {
    "id": 35,
    "question": "Frank is taller then John, and Harry is taller then Frank. Who is taller among all?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Harry",
    "b": "Frank",
    "c": "John",
    "d": "None of these"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Harry",
    "score": 0,
    "status": "a"
    },
    // -----------------------------end---------
        // ---------------------------start--------
    {
    "id": 36,
    "question": "What is 20% of 170?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "44",
    "b": "34",
    "c": "27",
    "d": "42"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "34",
    "score": 0,
    "status": "a"
    },
    // -----------------------------end---------
        // ---------------------------start--------
    {
    "id": 37,
    "question": "A train covers 120km in one hour, then how much it will cover in 12 min?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "28km",
    "b": "24km",
    "c": "32km",
    "d": "36km"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "24km",
    "score": 0,
    "status": "a"
    },
    // -----------------------------end---------
        // ---------------------------start--------
    {
    "id": 38,
    "question": "One dozen pencils price is 60, then what will be the price of 5?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "30",
    "b": "12",
    "c": "25",
    "d": "5"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "25",
    "score": 0,
    "status": "a"
    },
    // -----------------------------end---------
        // ---------------------------start--------
    {
    "id": 39,
    "question": "What will come next in the following series 3 9 27 81.....?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "243",
    "b": "247",
    "c": "353",
    "d": "157"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "243",
    "score": 0,
    "status": "a"
    },
    // -----------------------------end---------
        // ---------------------------start--------
    {
    "id": 40,
    "question": "Ajmal and Ahmed kept 24 balls. Ajmal kept 3 times then Ahmed. How much Ahmed kept?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "12",
    "b": "4",
    "c": "8",
    "d": "6"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "6",
    "score": 0,
    "status": "a"
    },
    // -----------------------------end---------
        // ---------------------------start--------
    {
    "id": 41,
    "question": "When Farooq and Saleem is 5 years old, their sister is 3 times older then them. What will be the age of their sister when they are 15 years old?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "45",
    "b": "25",
    "c": "30",
    "d": "None of these"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "25",
    "score": 0,
    "status": "a"
    },
    // -----------------------------end---------
        // ---------------------------start--------
    {
    "id": 42,
    "question": "One mile is equal to how many kilometer's?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "1.7",
    "b": "1.5",
    "c": "1.6",
    "d": "1.4"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "1.6",
    "score": 0,
    "status": "a"
    },
    // -----------------------------end---------
    //     // ---------------------------start--------
    // {
    // "id": 30,
    // "question": "?",
    // "options": [
    // {
    // "a": "",
    // "b": "",
    // "c": "",
    // "d": ""
    // }
    // ],
    // "answer": "",
    // "score": 0,
    // "status": "a"
    // },
    // // -----------------------------end---------
       

  

    ]
    }
    var quizApp = function () {
    this.score = 0;
    this.qno = 1;
    this.currentque = 0;
    var totalque = quiz.JS.length;
    this.displayQuiz = function (cque) {
    this.currentque = cque;
    if (this.currentque < totalque) {
    $("#tque").html(totalque);
    $("#previous").attr("disabled", false);
    $("#next").attr("disabled", false);
    $("#qid").html(quiz.JS[this.currentque].id + '.');
    $("#question").html(quiz.JS[this.currentque].question);
    $("#question-options").html("");
    for (var key in quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0]) {
    if (quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0].hasOwnProperty(key)) {
    $("#question-options").append(
    "<div class='form-check option-block'>" +
    "<label class='form-check-label'>" +
    "<input type='radio' class='form-check-input' name='option' id='q" + key + "' value='" + quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0][key] + "'><span id='optionval'>" +
    quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0][key] +
    "</span></label>"
    );
    }
    }
    }
    if (this.currentque <= 0) {
    $("#previous").attr("disabled", true);
    }
    if (this.currentque >= totalque) {
    $('#next').attr('disabled', true);
    for (var i = 0; i < totalque; i++) {
    this.score = this.score + quiz.JS[i].score;
    }
    return this.showResult(this.score);
    }
    }
    this.showResult = function (scr) {
    $("#result").addClass('result');
    $("#result").html("<h1 class='res-header'>Total Score: &nbsp;" + scr + '/' + totalque + "</h1>");
    for (var j = 0; j < totalque; j++) {
    var res;
    if (quiz.JS[j].score == 0) {
    res = '<span class="wrong">' + quiz.JS[j].score + '</span><i class="fa fa-remove c-wrong"></i>';
    } else {
    res = '<span class="correct">' + quiz.JS[j].score + '</span><i class="fa fa-check c-correct"></i>';
    }
    $("#result").append(
    '<div class="result-question"><span>Q ' + quiz.JS[j].id + '</span> &nbsp;' + quiz.JS[j].question + '</div>' +
    '<div><b>Correct answer:</b> &nbsp;' + quiz.JS[j].answer + '</div>' +
    '<div class="last-row"><b>Score:</b> &nbsp;' + res +
    '</div>'
    );
    }
    }
    this.checkAnswer = function (option) {
    var answer = quiz.JS[this.currentque].answer;
    option = option.replace(/</g, "&lt;") //for <
    option = option.replace(/>/g, "&gt;") //for >
    option = option.replace(/"/g, "&quot;")
    if (option == quiz.JS[this.currentque].answer) {
    if (quiz.JS[this.currentque].score == "") {
    quiz.JS[this.currentque].score = 1;
    quiz.JS[this.currentque].status = "correct";
    }
    } else {
    quiz.JS[this.currentque].status = "wrong";
    }
    }
    this.changeQuestion = function (cque) {
    this.currentque = this.currentque + cque;
    this.displayQuiz(this.currentque);
    }
    }
    var jsq = new quizApp();
    var selectedopt;
    $(document).ready(function () {
    jsq.displayQuiz(0);
    $('#question-options').on('change', 'input[type=radio][name=option]', function (e) {
    //var radio = $(this).find('input:radio');
    $(this).prop("checked", true);
    selectedopt = $(this).val();
    });
    });
    $('#next').click(function (e) {
    e.preventDefault();
    if (selectedopt) {
    jsq.checkAnswer(selectedopt);
    }
    jsq.changeQuestion(1);
    });
    $('#previous').click(function (e) {
    e.preventDefault();
    if (selectedopt) {
    jsq.checkAnswer(selectedopt);
    }
    jsq.changeQuestion(-1);
    });